A few months ago, I wrote a few
sentences, about four sentences, that
have turned out to be the most
influential four sentences I've ever
written. I packaged these four sentences
up into the Grill Me skill, which is a
skill that you can use to get the LLM to
interview you relentlessly. It
interviews you until you reach a shared
understanding, walking down each branch
of the design tree, resolving
dependencies between decisions one by
one. I know this skill is influential
because every single day I receive about
five messages of people saying they've
tried it and they love it. This skill is
an absolute game-changer. What are your
favorite skills? Grill Me is great. I'm
working on a project, blah blah blah.
The Grill Me skill asks me about
ambiguities. Fantastic. Grill Me skill
is goated. At first, I felt like it
slowed me down with all the questions,
but after using it a bit, I honestly
think it might save time. You just
one-shot everything after you've kind of
gathered all the context. Have you
tested the skill called Grill Me? And
blah blah blah blah blah. It's
wonderful, wonderful, wonderful,
wonderful. And after all that praise,
you might think, well, you should
probably stick with that skill,
shouldn't you? That skill sounds pretty
good. And it turns out I've actually
built a better one. I'm never very happy
when I'm resting on my laurels. I always
feel like there's improvements to be
made at every single part of my process.
And now, Grill Me has been replaced with
a new skill. Let's open up a session so
that I can explain a little bit more
about where Grill Me goes wrong. I'm
going to paste in a prompt that I've
already added here. And this prompt is
an idea for a new feature. I've just
dictated this out, so you just sort of
be spared the details of it. But
essentially, I want to create a new
entity in my database, and a new entity
that my app is going to deal with.
Currently, this application deals in
courses, deals in lessons, deals in
videos, and you know, sections and a few
other things. And I want to add a
concept of pitches. There's this kind of
Mr. Beast style axiom where you should
be thinking about the packaging for your
video before you actually work out
what's going in the video. And that's
what a pitch is in this kind of setup. A
pitch is really just the packaging for
the video, the title, the description,
how I'm going to frame it to people, and
I create a bunch of these pitches and
then pick the best ones and then turn
those into videos. Now, what you notice
here is as I'm communicating with the
agent, I we're really focusing on
language, right? We're really focusing
on what is a pitch. I just had to
communicate that to you so that you
could follow along, and the agent will
need to extract that information from
me, too. But, there's also some extra
jargon in here that the agent doesn't
know about yet. For instance, I'm
talking about stand-alone videos. What
does a stand-alone video mean? Oh, of
course, it means a video that's not
connected to a lesson or a course. Now,
of course, I know that. That's kind of
like a term of art for using this whole
set up, but the agent doesn't know that
yet. It doesn't have any concept of what
that is. So, during the grilling
session, it's going to have to ask me
what a stand-alone video is or try to
figure it out from the code. So, as I
used Grill me more and more and more, I
would start to notice these times where
the agent was being really, really
verbose and I would have to remind it,
"No, there's already a term for that."
And often though, there wasn't a term or
I was kind of thinking about things in a
very verbose way myself and that wasn't
being challenged by the agent. Or, we
would actually land on some really good
shared language and then that wasn't
documented anywhere. So, I started to
feel dissatisfied with Grill me because
there was this piece missing from the
puzzle, which is we were able to
communicate about the code pretty
effectively, but I would have to
re-explain all of the non-obvious things
about the code base and about the
domain, the problem that we were solving
before we could do anything productive.
So, I started to think to myself, what
is the thinnest layer of documentation I
could use to just give the AI a bit more
of a leg up. So, I came up with this
skill, the ubiquitous language skill.
Ubiquitous language is an idea that
comes from domain-driven design. This is
the big blue book by Eric Evans that
everyone goes on about. And what it
does, it's it's essentially you're
trying to create a document, which is
the language that's used by the code
base, that's used by developers, and
that's used by domain experts. In other
words, people that know about what
you're building, but not how you're
building it. All of those three groups
should be using a shared language,
because that means that the domain
expert can go, "Okay, there's something
wrong with this particular section of
the app." The developer knows what
they're talking about, and the code also
reflects that. So, what I would do is in
the middle of a grilling session, when I
noticed that we were needed to sharpen
some language, I would use the
ubiquitous language skill and call it
with, you know, ubiquitous language, and
try to create a ubiquitous language.md
as we were going. So, I had grill me and
I had ubiquitous language, and I was
using them both at the same time, and I
realized, "Wouldn't it be great if I
just combine the two into a new skill?"
And here is that new skill. It is grill
with docs. It has exactly the same text
as grill me at the top here, but it has
a couple of extra pieces. The first
thing it has is the ability to look for
a context.md file. This context.md file
will have document all of the shared
language that's inside that context.
Now, context is like super overloaded,
so I'm sort of uncomfortable, but maybe
okay with it. It's essentially a bounded
context in DDD is a part of the app in
which you speak a shared language. So,
if you have a massive mono repo, you can
have a context map here and have many
different contexts inside. So, that's
how you would scale this to an enormous
repo. But still, if you just have one
pretty big repo where all the
application is speaking the same
language and the domain expert speak the
same language, then you can just use a
single context.md here. So, it's
instructed to look for this existing
documentation to pull in this shared
language, and then during the session
it's got some extra additions here to
challenge uh language usage against the
existing glossary, to sharpen fuzzy
language, discuss concrete scenarios,
cross-reference with code, and update it
as you go. So, this essentially helps
you really sharpen your language as
you're using the Grill with Docs skill.
And this pays off as you go. I was
asking some folks for feedback on this,
and I got some really nice quotes here.
So, this guy used it for the whole of
today, and at the start it asked him to
define a lot of terms. Some terms were
hard to agree on, and ones he would most
definitely forget. But four or five
sessions in, he started noticing that
Claude was picking up the context during
the Grill session, and it magically
aligned with the thoughts I had before
the words came out of that brain. So,
that's what you get out of this. By
documenting the non-obvious stuff, by
agreeing on a shared language, you
really can nail down and get a magical
alignment between you and the AI, where
you just have to use far fewer words to
communicate what you mean. For instance,
here's the one that I have in my repo
here. We essentially just have a little
description about what the um, you know,
what the repo is. Then we have a course
and a course repo, and we have all of
the entities inside here, course
versions as well, because I have
multiple versions. And if we look for
the one that we were looking at before,
which is standalone
video, it is just down here. So, we have
an exact specification for what
standalone video means now. Now, the
Grill with Docs skill knows to look for
this, but I also add a context pointer
into, not inside that claw.md, but
inside the local claw.md here. So, we
have just this domain docs, a single
context layout, context.md at the repo
root, and you see this extra little bit
of uh, documentation for more
information about where this stuff is.
One final thing that Grill with Docs
does is that there are some things that
sharpening the fuzzy language will help
with, but there are some things that it
won't. And so, I wanted a layer that
would explain all the non-obvious
decisions that weren't able to be
captured inside context.md. And so for
that, I've gone with an architectural
decision record. These ADRs here are
really like simple markdown files that
sit in your repo that essentially
document all of the non-obvious
decisions. You only want to create an
ADR when the decision is hard to reverse
because if it's just like oh we'll use
this library instead of this library and
they're kind of interchangeable, then
you can always just swap later.
It would be surprising without context.
And plenty of decisions in a repo are
surprising without context, especially
more complex ones, and the result of a
real trade-off. In other words, that
this decision has consequences down the
line. And I've got an ADR format inside
here that um the LLM uses when it
creates these ADRs. So now we understand
all the pieces, let's go back up to
here. Let's replace grill me with grill
with docs, and let's actually start this
grilling session to see it in action.
All right, so the first thing it has
done is it said "Ooh, context.md is
rich. Standalone video is already
defined as a lessier
a video with lesson ID equals null." And
it says before going further, I want to
surface attention with the glossary.
This is what you'll often find with
grill with docs is that it really
focuses on the language before you then
actually go and talk about
implementation details. It says there's
cardinality between pitch and standalone
video. It's asking whether one pitch
holds many standalone videos or one
pitch corresponds to exactly one
standalone video. I think it might make
sense to follow its recommendation here
and go with okay, we have one to many
relationship here. So I'm just going to
say correct. Very nice. Next up, it's
noticing that there's a terminology
collision with the standalone video. So
it's saying that you have a standalone
video that are either totally standalone
or they can be related to pitches. So I
think it's basically asking whether we
keep standalone video as any pitched or
unpitched lesson
or we redefine it to mean specifically
unpitched unlessoned video. Now the way
we answer this question is going to
influence everything afterwards. It's
going to influence whether standalone
videos get their own section in the UI
or whether we have standalone videos and
videos with pitches kind of mixed in.
Because the language that we're defining
here is also the language that the user
is going to be seeing on the page when
they navigate around this. And I think
I'm agreeing with it. Actually, I was
actually going into this thinking we
would probably have a separate section
for pitched videos, but I think yes, I
agree. It makes sense to keep pitching
as just metadata on the standalone video
itself. This, by the way, is Whisper
Flow, what I'm using for dictation. It
works okay. I'm not sure I'd recommend
it, but it's fine. It's now saying,
"Okay, we need some status semantics
here." So, each pitch can be idle or
scheduled or shipped here. I think I
want just to allow I think I want to
allow just free-form transitions. So, I
don't really care about this being
automated. We can always layer on
automation later, you know, like when
you press uh send to YouTube or
something, it goes into a new status.
But for now, I'm okay just like toggling
it myself. That's fine. It's now asking,
"Can a pitch exist with zero videos?"
Absolutely, a pitch can exist with zero
videos. The point here is that we're
kind of generating um pitches, ideas for
videos, you know? This is the Mr. Beast
thing. We're trying to uh
get the packaging ready first. And this
relationship, this language also goes
into things as concrete as deletion
cascades. So, I think I'm going to say
on delete restrict here. This is mostly
because I just uh like um restrictive
deletions. And mostly what I do is I
tend to archive instead of delete when I
actually do these. We're now getting
into more implementation details here.
So, I think um instead of just boring
you with actually like implementing the
grilling session here, I'm just going to
say, "Could you save what we have into
context.md so far?" If there's anything
we haven't figured out, grill me about
that before you make the adjustments.
And let's see what it goes for here. And
okay, it has made a bunch of updates
into context.md. Specifically, it's
added a bunch of pitch information here.
So, we've got pitch, the actual entity
itself. We've got pitch status, the
status the pitch can be in. Pitched
standalone video is a little bit
awkward. I might want to grill it about
that. And then unattached standalone
video. That's also like So, it's
basically saying standalone standalone
video. Now, bear in mind, I'm like I
might seem like pretty, you know,
anal-retentive about this language. This
might just feel like bike-shedding to
you. But, this is going to affect every
part of the code that's generated. All
variable names, all file names are going
to be based on these uh context.md
documents here. And so, getting this
right is absolutely crucial for feeling
aligned with the AI. Now, of course, we
don't want to just endlessly bike-shed.
So, I'm going to call this now. I'm
going to say that's good enough. Let's
ship with this. We can always change and
refactor to new language later. So,
let's quickly talk about the benefits
here. What you actually get from going
through this ceremony. thing that you
get is concise replies. The AI is able
to use fewer tokens to speak to you
because you have this shared language
and it doesn't need to verbosely repeat
everything or re-describe everything. It
just says, "Okay, standalone videos are
changing. We needed to make a change to
the pitches and how the pitches
display." This concision is also
reflected in its own thinking traces as
well. Because, of course, AI uses
language to think to itself. And so,
it's able to be much more aligned with
your intention and actually use fewer
tokens thinking. This is something I've
observed and it feels pretty nice. And
finally, because the planning documents,
because the way that you're speaking
with the AI is also aligned with the way
the code looks as well, then you end up
with easier to navigate code. Because
it's able to just, "Okay, I need to find
all the information about pitches. Let
me just search for it." And of course,
this makes sense because these are all
the same benefits described in
domain-driven design itself. So, the
same techniques that work with humans
also, it turns out, work with AI. You're
thinking though, is Grill me dead? Did I
just kill Grill me? Did its creator come
along and stab it in the back?
Absolutely not. I think Grill me is an
excellent excellent skill, but Grill
with Docs is better when you have a code
base. In my skills, I have moved Grill
me into the productivity area here. So,
this is for general use cases, for use
cases where you don't have a code base.
I had someone, this is the most amazing
story, who said that they were writing a
eulogy for their mom, and they used
Grill me to get the AI to grill them
about their mom and surface all these
amazing stories. And so, Grill me has
incredible use cases outside of
engineering. And of course, if you are
really early on in a project, actually
really early on a project, I'd still
probably recommend using Grill with Docs
because you just get so much more out of
that shared language, and often at the
start of a project is where you're
trying to establish that shared
language. So, essentially, the rule is
when you have a code base, use Grill
with Docs. When you don't have a code
base, use Grill me. I update these
skills super duper regularly, and I'm
often thinking new thoughts about the
skills or even how best to use them
without changing the skills themselves.
So, I keep everyone up to date on this
with my AI skills for real engineers
newsletter. This is just an addition to
the already good newsletter that I have
that just gives you a few extra skills
updates, or maybe one a week when they
happen. I really freaking hate email
spam, and so I'm not going to spam you,
but this little page will help you
basically keep up to date with all the
skill change logs and have some nice
extra additions here that you can just
take a look at and learn how to use the
skills better. Otherwise, thanks for
watching, and I'll see you in the next
one. Thank you so much for following
along. I really really appreciate it.
And if you enjoy this skill, then do let
me know in the comments how you got on
with it, what you noticed, and do raise
an issue on the skills repo itself if
you think there's something that I can
improve.